A Guide to the Makely Family Papers, 1859-1865
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Makely Family Papers, 1859-1865
Library of Virginia
27034
.90 cubic feet (2 boxes)
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Mrs. Ivan M. Green through A.C. Murdaugh, 16 December 1968.
Biographical/Historical Information
Wesley (b. 1835) and Catherine Appich Makely (b. 1841) were from Alexandria, Virginia. Wesley Makely served as captain of Company D, 18th Virginia Cavalry. He was captured 9 July 1863 near Hancock, Maryland, and sent to Johnson's Island (Oh) from 18 July 1863 to 21 March 1865, then to Pt. Lookout (Md), and released from Ft. Delaware (Del.) on 9 May 1865.
Scope and Content Information
Papers, 1859-1865, of the Makely family of Alexandria, Virginia. The bulk of the collection consists of letters written between Wesley and Kate Makely, while Wesley was in prison at Johnson's Island, Ohio. Topics include family, health, care packages, jewelry made by camp prisoners, attempts to obtain a parole for Wesley, weather, and prison regulations. Of note is a day book, dated 1863-1865, kept by Wesley at Johnson's Island. The day book contains an alphabetical list of prisoners held at Johnson's Island, including their name, rank, regiment, residence, place captured and date. The daybook also includes lists of prisoners who died at Johnson's Island, lists of generals, lieutenant generals, major generals, and brigadier generals of the Confederate army, a sketch of the prison compound, and poetry written by prisoners. The collection also includes a deed for land in Fairfax County (Va.) dated 1859, receipts for money transfers, telegrams, business cards, photographs, envelopes, loyalty oath of Wesley 9 May 1865, and prison visitor passes for Kate Makely.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged alphabetically by folder title.
Contents List
- Correspondence, Wesley Makely to Kate Makely, 1863 December-1864 May (Box-folder Box 1 Folder 1)
- Correspondence, Wesley Makely to Kate Makely, 1864 June-October (Box-folder Box 1 Folder 2)
- Correspondence, Wesley Makely to Kate Makely, 1864 November-1865 April (Box-folder Box 1 Folder 3)
- Correspondence, Kate Makely to Wesley Makely, 1863 August-1864 April (Box-folder Box 1 Folder 4)
- Correspondence, Kate Makely to Wesley Makely, 1864 May-June (Box-folder Box 1 Folder 5)
- Correspondence, Kate Makely to Wesley Makely, 1864 June-November (Box-folder Box 1 Folder 6)
- Correspondence, Kate Makely to Wesley Makely, 1864 December-1865 April (Box-folder Box 1 Folder 7)
- Correspondence, Miscellaneous 1863-1865 (Box-folder Box 2 Folder 1)
- Daybook, 1863-1865 (Box-folder Box 2 Folder 2)
- Miscellaneous 1859-1865 (Box-folder Box 2 Folder 3)